<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Record Store Day on Yoshiharu Yamashita</title>
    <link>http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/tags/record-store-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Record Store Day on Yoshiharu Yamashita</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 09:08:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/tags/record-store-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking out Rise Bristol on Record Store Day 2016</title>
      <link>http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/post/checking-out-rise-bristol-on-record-store-day-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 09:08:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/post/checking-out-rise-bristol-on-record-store-day-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;On an unseasonably chilly mid-April morning, my missus and I went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rise-music.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Rise&lt;/a&gt; in Bristol to experience &lt;a href=&#34;http://recordstoreday.co.uk/home/&#34;&gt;Record Store Day&lt;/a&gt; for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;queuing-up-is-part-of-the-fun:edd8f465df994f9c038da684c17d5666&#34;&gt;Queuing up is Part of the Fun?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read somewhere that some vinyl fans would start queuing up really early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are not that dedicated (yet), we got there at about 11am and guess what? There was a long queue. The record section is upstairs and there were staff controlling access to the floor above. Live music was performed at the ground floor where the cafe (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.friskafood.com/&#34;&gt;Friska&lt;/a&gt;) is.  This should have made the queuing up less boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the queue was not moving much. Feeling peckish we decided to come back after having lunch. As we left the store, one of the exclusive vinyl releases in the shop window caught my eye. It was &lt;strong&gt;Moseley Shoals - Ocean Colour Scene&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be the one I would buy had I the choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-attempt:edd8f465df994f9c038da684c17d5666&#34;&gt;Second Attempt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we came back to the store for the second time there was no queue nor any staff controlling entrance to the first floor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first floor was full of people and a DJ was playing a collection of music on impressive looking record decks. The atomosphere was very pleasant with good sound quality music. we could really see how popular the event was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-first-record-purchases-ever:edd8f465df994f9c038da684c17d5666&#34;&gt;Our First Record Purchases Ever&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsing the floor, my missus picked up this one:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;pure-u-1-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;pure-img&#34; src=&#34;http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/img/post/jimi-hendrix-smash-hits.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jimi Hendrix - Smash Hits&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format: Standard 12&amp;rdquo; Black LP Vinyl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label: Sony CMG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Info: Limited to 5000 copies. Restored from original 1969 format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while but I was happy to find what I was after in the end:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;pure-u-1-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;pure-img&#34; src=&#34;http://yoshiharuyamashita.com/img/post/ocean-colour-scene-moseley-shoals.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ocean Colour Scene - Moseley Shoals&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format: 2LP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label: UMC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Info: 20th anniversary edition on red vinyl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was whopping £35 though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not planning to spend that much for a record but I would hate regretting not buying it. So I went ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall:edd8f465df994f9c038da684c17d5666&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was a fun day being part of the event, flipping through records amongst enthusiastic fans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some Record Store Day releases were very pricey perhaps due to their limited availability. Good job the event is held only once a year :p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official website lists all the exclusive releases in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://recordstoreday.co.uk/media/2711/product-listing-6apr.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF file&lt;/a&gt; but no price information is included. It would not be too much to ask to include it in the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this I have to admit that our record player has still not been delivered yet so we cannot listen to the records. For now all we can do is to admire what we have bought and wait patiently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>